Finding Aid for the The Sigaux Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Jules Renard (dossier gris) Jules Renard (grey dossier). Press clippings, journal excerpts, book catalog and advertisement pages (includes pamphlet from La Belle Édition), correspondence (typed copies, to Steinlen from Jules Renard), typed and handwritten manuscripts (includes a G. S. preface, chronology, and bibliography), correspondence (a large packet of letters to G. S. from Léon Guichard), typed transcripts (speeches, radio), correspondence (to G. S. from Pierre Béarn), printed biographical and bibliographical notecards, auction catalog page, correspondence (from Docteur L. Tixier), book excerpts, G. S. notes, professional correspondence (to G. S. from Robert Meiffredy of La Belle Édition), b&w photo, photocopy of genelogy report, booklet (a commemorative booklet inscribed to G. S., includes transcript of a 1909 J. Renard speech at the school bearing his name), periodical (Le Bulletin des Lettres), booklet (commemorative booklet relating the inauguration of a bust of Jules Renard, includes the transcribed speeches from the event), exhibit catalog (Jules Renard (1864-1910) L'Homme et l'Oeuvre, Bibliothèque Universitaire de Grenoble). (Box 67, Folder 1)
- Jules Renard Jules Renard. Press clippings, journal and book excerpts (includes photocopies and G. S. articles), G. S. notes and notes in a different hand, correspondence (to G. S. from Léon Guichard), typed transcript (radio), typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. articles and prefaces: Génies du Théâtre Français, Tome 39: Le Pain de Ménage; Un Portrait de Jules Renard; Le Théâtre de Jules Renard; La Demande - 1895; Le Plaisir de Rompre - 1897; Le Pain de Ménage - 1898; Le Poil de Carotte - 1900; Monsieur Vernet - 1903; La Bigote - 1909; Le Cousin de Rose; "Quand, de 1925 à 1927, parut ce Journal..."), typed notes (character index notes from Pascal Pia). (Box 67, Folder 2)
- Sévigné Marie de Rabutin-Chantal, Marquise de Sévigné. Journal excerpts, G. S. notes, typed manuscripts (G. S. articles and prefaces: 2 drafts of Dictionnaire des Personnages; 2 drafts of Préface; 3 drafts of Histoire des "Lettres" de Madame de Sévigné; Bibliographie; 2 drafts of Chronologie de la Vie de Madame de Sévigné; 2 drafts of Avant-Propos; 1 draft of Liste des Lettres). (Box 67, Folder 3)
- Shakespeare William Shakespeare. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. preface and articles: J'ai lu l'essentiel. 8 juillet 1963: Shakespeare; La Mégère Apprivoisée; Macbeth; Jules César; La Tempete; 3 drafts of Les Théâtres à Londres de 1576 à 1642; Troupes et Comédiens en Angleterre au XVIe Siècle; Shakespeare en France; Shakespeare sur la scène Française; Le Mystère; Le Puritanisme Contre le Théâtre), professional correspondence (to G. S. from Frédéric Ditis of J'ai Lu, and to G. S. from Jean-Pierre Vivet). (Box 67, Folder 4)
- Simenon - G. S. Georges Simenon. Press clippings (includes photocopies and G. S. articles), journal excerpts (includes photocopies and G. S. articles), periodicals (off print of dossiers du CACEF, and illustré avec télé hebdo), correspondence (to M. André Asseo), b&w photo (illustration/drawing of G. Simenon), correspondence (to G. S. from Marc Simenon), professional correspondence (memo to Jean-Marc Dabadie from Pierre Deligny), invitation (to the opening of an exhibit on Simenon and the cinema), G. S. notes, professional correspondence (to G. S. from F. de Lulle), professional correspondence (to André Asseo from Georges Simenon), professional correspondence (to G. S. from Polydor Société Anonyme), professional correspondence (to G. S. from Robert Dewez of radiodiffusion-télévision belge), contract with radiodiffusion-télévision belge, typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. articles and prefaces: Disques Georges Simenon {interview questions - ?}; Georges Simenon (né en 1903): Romancier; 4 drafts of Lire Simenon; 2 drafts of Georges Simenon: Romancier; Érivains d'aujourd'hui: Georges Simenon; Simenon Cet Inconnu; Georges Simenon; 2 drafts of La Disparition d'Odile; 3 drafts of Simenon, Tome 1: Maigret avant Maigret; 3 drafts of Simenon, Tome V: Avant-Propos; 2 drafts of Simenon, Maigret VI: Avant-Propos; Simenon, Maigret VIII: Avant-Propos; Simenon, Maigret IX: Avant-Propos; Simenon, Maigret, Tome XII: Avant-Propos; XV: Avant-Propos; XXV: Avant-Propos; 2 drafts of Simenon, Tome I: Avant-Propos; Tome 3, (Note); Note; Avec Georges Simenon; 2 drafts of a G. S. preface, "Quand il s'agit..."; L'Amie de Madame Maigret), book advertisement pages (including pamphlet with G. S. text), typed chronology and filmography, book excerpts (G. S. preface and articles), correspondence (to G. S. from Docteur Pierre Debray), professional correspondence (to G. S. from May McKenna of Folens and Co., Ltd.), typed manuscripts (3 articles for a special school edition of l'Amie de Madame Maigret, not by G. S.), correspondence (to G. Simenon from G. S.). (Box 67, Folder 5)
- Vallès Jules Vallès (Louis-Jules Vallez). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. play text and articles: Jules Vallès: La Jeunesse d'un réfractaire; Chronologie de la Vie et de l'oeuvre de Jules Vallès, 1832-1885; Note sur "l'Enfant"; 3 drafts of Le Bachelier; 2 drafts of l'Insurgé; 2 drafts of 1870-1871: De la fin du Second Empire à la fin de la Commune), G. S. notes. (Box 67, Folder 6)
- Zola Émile Zola. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles, includes off-prints), invitation to "Pélerinage Littéraire de Médan" (a series of lectures honoring Émile Zola; given by Gaëtan Picon, G. S., and Henri Mitterrand), book advertisement pamphlets (2 copies, includes a chronology and a G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. articles and prefaces: Zola, Tome 33: Zola et le Théâtre (I); Zola, Tome 34: Zola et le Théâtre (II); Les Livres Qui Ont Fait Le Monde: Émile Zola - La Verité en Marche, Avant-Propos; Chronologie de la Vie et des Oeuvres d'Émile Zola; L'Homme et son Oeuvre; Les Rougon-Macquart; Zola journaliste, de l'affaire Manet à l'affaire Dreyfus; 2 drafts of Zola: Mélanges, Préfaces et Discours - Préface; 3 drafts of La République en Marche - Avant-Propos; Zola Correspondance: Préface; 2 drafts of Zola, Tome 32: Le Roman Expérimental. Les Romanciers Naturalistes; Préface: Nos Auteurs Dramatiques et Documents Littéraires; Préface: Une Campagne et Nouvelle Campagne; {"Les Rougon-Macquart" en 1962}), press clippings (G. S. articles), printed transcripts (2 copies of a G. S. lecture), a Cercle du Bibliophile folder with reproductions of the illustrations (by TIM) from the complete works of Émile Zola. (Box 67, Folder 7)